大家好，漂亮的人们，在上一个视频中，你们看到了如何重定向标准输出。
Hello you beautiful people so in the last video you saw how to redirect standard output.
在这段视频中，我们将继续学习如何重定向标准
And in this video we're going to be picking that up and continuing by learning how to redirect standard
时代和标准输入。
era and standard input.
所以让我们从标准误差开始。
So let's start with standard error.
你怎么把它重定向。
How do you go about redirecting that.
嗯，有些作品的标准输出方式与标准输出的数字非常相似
Well some of there are works in very much the same way a standard output than the number for the standard
错误数据流是要排序的重定向标准错误的编号。
error data stream is the number to sort of redirects standard error.
您可以键入cat，然后不是1，然后是同意和未签名，这就是我们用来表示标准的
You would type cat and then instead of one and then agree and unsigned which is what we use for standard
您只需输出，因为标准错误的数据流是第二个。
output you just have to because the data stream of a standard error is number two.
这会将标准错误从cat命令重定向到Arundhati ex-state并追加
And this would redirect the standard error from the cat command to Arundhati ex-state and to append
对任何已经处于干燥状态的东西的标准误差xTi，你可以做两个箭头。
the standard error to whatever is already in aridity XTi you would do the two arrows.
请记住，单箭头和双箭头之间的区别在于，单箭头将删除所有内容
So remember the difference between the one arrow and the two arrows is the one arrow will delete everything
在写入之前，它在文件中，在钢笔之前，所以它会截断文件。
that's in the file before a pen before writing to it and so it will truncate the file.
两个箭头将附加或添加到已有的内容上。
And two arrows will append or add to what already there.
好的，让我们来演示一下。
OK so let's demonstrate this.
cat的命令没有k选项。
The cat's command doesn't have the k option.
好的，如果我做了cat，给它k选项，然后输入blah。
OK so if I do cat give it the k option and just type blah.
正确的。
Right.
我们将收到一个错误，它将显示无效选项。
We're going to get an error and it's going to say Invalid option.
K试试猫的帮助。
K try cat help.
了解更多信息。
For more information.
所以这是一条错误消息。
So this is an error message.
因此，它在标准错误数据流上输出，默认情况下，标准数据流是
So therefore it was output on the standard error data stream and the standard data stream is by default
连接到终端，因此我们在终端中看到。
connected to a terminal and therefore we see in our terminal.
但是让我们把它重定向到Arundhati XTi。
But let's redirect it to Arundhati XTi.
所以不为所动的UP可以省去一些打字时间，我要输入数字2，然后
So unimpressed the up are ok to save myself some typing and I'm going to type the number two and then
一个很棒的未签名的，并说重定向到RTX XTi。
a great unsigned and say redirect that to RTX XTi.
好的，我的意思是，运行这个，然后将Sendero重定向到Arati Active。
OK so I'm saying Run this and redirect the the Sendero to Arati active.
因此，当我按Enter键时，我们首先注意到终端上没有弹出任何东西，这是一个好消息
So when I press Enter we first of all we notice that nothing popped out on our terminal which is a good
签名。
sign.
当我们打开我们的文件时，我们可以看到有一个叫做特技飞行的文件。
When we open up our files we can see there's a file called aerobatics.
当我打开它时，我们可以看到错误消息确实已经发送到该位置。
And when I open it we can see that indeed the error message has been sent to that location.
这种用于重定向标准错误的常见用法是跟踪传入的日志消息
A common use for this kind of for redirecting standard error is to keep track of log messages coming
从Web服务器和诸如此类的东西。
from web servers and things like that.
但一个常见的错误是只使用一个箭头，就像我们这里一样。
But a common mistake is to use just one arrow like we have here.
好的。
OK.
因为如果我一直这样做，这意味着它会在发送之前删除文件中的内容。
Because if I keep doing that what that means is it will delete what's in the file before before it sends.
如果我一直做OK，就会出现标准错误。
Standard error against If I keep doing the OK.
想象一下，每一次都会有一个新的时代发生。
Imagine a new era happens every time.
好的。
OK.
如果我继续做露天0.60，只保存了最近的错误。
If I keep doing an open air 0.60 only the most recent error has been saved.
但是如果我有一支箭，而不是一支箭，我有两支箭。
But if my Instead of having one arrow I have two arrows.
现在我要把每个区域叠加在一起。
Now I'm going to append each area on top of each other.
好的。
OK.
这正是您希望使用日志文件的原因，因为您希望能够回滚并查看
Which is exactly what you want with a log file because you want to be able to scroll back and see what's
过去发生过，因为它又开了。
happened in the past because it's open again.
现在我们可以看到错误是叠加在一起的。
Now we can see that the errors are being added on top of each other.
所以这就是有一个箭头和两个箭头的区别，两个箭头用笔写在什么上面
So that's the difference between having the one arrow and the two arrows the two arrows pens onto what
已经在那里了。
was already there.
好的。
OK.
这才是标准时代真正需要的。
And that's really what you need for standard era.
现在，您当然可以同时重定向标准错误和标准输出。
Now you can of course redirect standard error and standard output at the same time.
例如，我们可以键入cat命令，然后将输出重定向到输出RTX测试成员标准
So for example we could type the cat command and redirect output to output RTX t member that standard
输出1号数据流，我们还可以将标准错误重定向到另一个称为错误的位置
output data stream number one and we could also redirect standard error to another place called error
xti，我们可以通过确保在两个箭头上的两个箭头，来确保我们已经添加了这两个箭头
XTi and we can make sure that we've that we append both of them by making sure the two arrows at both
地点。
places.
然后当我们开始的时候，像Linux这样的东西是令人惊叹的。
And then when we start something like Linux is amazing.
然后当我们在这里打开文件浏览器时取消。
And then we cancel when we open up our file browser here.
我们将看到我们现在有两个文件。
We will see that we now have two files.
我想看看有两个输出的输出。
I would like to see an output that takes two output.
DXi包含Linux是惊人的，标准错误，实际上不包含东西的错误，因为
DXi contains Linux is amazing and standard error the error that actually doesn't contain thing because
此输出实际上没有错误。
there were actually no errors from this output.
这是一个完全有效的命令，不需要任何错误，但这就是您要执行的操作
It was a perfectly valid command there were no errors required but that is how you would go about doing
它。
it.
这就是我们将标准输出重定向到输出的方式，实际上我们可以看出
So this is how we would we would be redirecting standard output to output to actually we can tell that
因为第一位在这里，标准错误在名为arity xti的文件中。
because the number one is here and standard error to a file called aridity XTi.
现在我们可以看到追加标准误差的数字和误差是多少，输出也是如此
Now we can see what the number and the error is that standard error would be appended and so would output
ATX T.
现在我们还记得，您实际上不需要一个输出文本，所以您可以这样做
Now we actually remember you actually don't need the one output text so you could actually just do that
确实可以说Linux是非常令人惊叹的。
and do say Linux is very amazing.
当我看它的时候，我们可以看到输出，它已经附加了文本。
And when I look at that we can see output it has had it's text appended.
同样，航空学上也不会有任何错误，因为没有任何错误。
And again there will still be no errors in aeronautics because there weren't any errors.
但是您可以在这里看到，即使不使用数字1，它仍然可以工作。
But you can see here that without using the number one this will still work.
但是您仍然需要标准错误的数字2，因为Shawk不可用。
But you do still need the number two for standard error because that Shawk isn't available.
好的。
OK.
所以你只能去掉第一位的标准输出数据流OK。
So you can only get rid of the number one for the standard output data stream OK.
非常出色。
Brilliant.
所以你知道我知道如何重定向标准输出和标准错误。
So you know I understand how to redirect standard output and standard error.
那么标准输入如何呢？
So how about standard input.
实际上，在cat命令正在寻找标准的时候，这是相对简单的
Well actually that's relatively straightforward at the moment the cat command is looking for standard
从键盘输入。
input from the keyboard.
如果我们告诉它从文件中获取标准输入，会怎么样？
What if we told it to get standard input from a file instead.
因此，让我们创建一个名为input RTX T的文件，并键入单词hello world。
So let's make a file called input RTX T and type in the words hello world.
所以我们要做的是使用cat命令，现在我们将输出到
I so what we're going to do is we're going to use the cat command and we'll get output that now to a
名为Input Datti XTi的文件。
file called input Datti XTi.
好的，我们可以做一个文件，我们要放进去。
OK so we can make a file We're going to put in there.
你好，世界。
Hello world.
现在，当我取消时，我们已经有效地创建了一个名为input ATX D的文件，在那里我们有。
Now when I cancel the we have now effectively created a file called input ATX D and in there we have.
你好，世界。
Hello world.
好的。
OK.
因此，您也可以看到如何使用重定向来创建这样的文件。
So you can see how you can use redirection to create files like this as well.
现在，让我们现在使用，让我们再次尝试使用cat命令读取该文件。
Now let's use now let's try and read from that file using the cat command again.
好的，我们怎样才能使这个文件的内容这个政治文件被读入标准输入
OK how can we make the contents of this file this in politics file be read into standard input for the
cat命令，这样我们以后就不需要键入它了，比方说。
cat command so that we don't have to type it later on let's say.
标准输入流的数字是零。
Well the standard input stream has the number of zero.
所以我们能做的就是键入数字0，而不是灰色的无符号，就像
So what we can do is we can type cat the number 0 and instead of the grey of unsigned which is like
实际使用小于号的输出。
an output you actually use the less than sign.
好的，我们说，然后输入RTX。
Ok we say then input RTX.
或者作为一条捷径。
Or as a shortcut.
因为标准输入流是您可以实际输入的唯一方式。
Because the standard input stream is the only way that you can actually input.
你甚至不需要零。
You don't even need the zero.
你只需在我背上签个字就行了。
You just put the less than sign my back.
现在，当我们这样做时，我们会看到屏幕上弹出hello world消息。
Now when we do this we see the hello world message pop up on the screen.
这是因为CAT已从标准输入读取文件并将其输出到标准输出，该标准输出
Now this is because cat has read the file from standard input and output it to standard output which
默认连接到我们的终端。
is by default connected to our terminal.
现在来个小挑战。
Now here's a mini challenge.
好的。
OK.
我希望您让CATS从输入ATX T读取标准输入，并将输出重定向到。
I want you to get cats to read standard input from input ATX T and redirect the output to.
你好，XTi医生。
Hello Dr. XTi.
并使之成为现实。
And make it so that that happens.
好的。
OK.
所以去吧，试一试吧。
So go ahead and give that a go.
现在暂停视频，并尝试让cat从他XTi的输入中读取标准输入，然后将
Pause the video now and try to get cat to read standard input from input that he XTi and redirect the
输出到hello itx然后他回来看看你做得怎么样
output to hello itx he then come back to see how you did
你做到了吗？这是我该怎么做的。
did you manage it was here's how I would go about it.
我将首先重定向cat标准输入，这样它就来自于他的XTi。
I would first redirect cat standard input so that it comes from that he XTi.
所以我们将按照法律来做，然后我会把它放到一个叫Hello Datti XTi的文件中。
So we're just going to do by law and then I would put it to a file called Hello Datti XTi.
好的。
OK.
现在为了便于阅读，我可能会添加流编号，所以我可能会说我要重定向到
Now to make it easier to read I might add the stream numbers so I might say I am going to redirect into
流0。
stream 0.
但是需要t，我将从流1重定向，它是标准输出，指向hello 0.60。
But it takes t and I'm going to redirect from stream 1 which is standard output to hello 0.60.
你用哪一个完全由你决定。
It's totally up to you which one you use.
这也许是一种方法。
This might be a way to do it.
可能不是，但请记住，在第一部分中，0是标准的，第一部分是放入标准误差的标准。
It might not be but just remember that 0 is standard in part one is standard put into standard error.
好的，在这里我们可以看到，我们正在将输入atx t读入标准输入。
OK and here we can see that we're reading input ATX t into standard input.
可以很容易地以图形方式看到这一点，我们正在将标准输出写入Hello
It's quite easy to see that quite quite graphically and we're writing from standard output into Hello
西蒂医生。
Dr. XTi.
好的。
OK.
所以如果我们现在继续这样做，我们应该能够看到，事实上，是的，我们现在有一个名为
So if we go ahead and do that now we should be able to see that in fact yes we now have a file called
你好，战术，当我们打开它的时候，我们会看到你好，世界。
Hello tactics and when we open it we see Hello world.
这不是很神奇吗。
Isn't that amazing.
这就是您可以重定向计算机上所有数据的方式。
That's how you can redirect data all around your computer.
现在还有一件令人兴奋的事情。
Now here's one more mindblowing thing.
Linux中的所有内容实际上都被视为文件。
Everything in Linux is actually treated the same as a file.
甚至是终端。
Even terminals.
让我打开另一个术语，使用快捷键Altamonte，我可以正确地打开它们
So let me open up another term along and use the shortcut control Altamonte and I get to open them right
放在一首歌旁边，把一首放在这里，我要把一首放在这里。
next to one of the song and put one over here and I'm going to put one over here.
好的。
OK.
现在在另一个航站楼，这个在右边的新航站楼上。
Now in the other terminal this one over this new one on the right.
我将运行T.T.y命令。
I'm going to run the T.T. y command.
现在，TDY命令实际上将告诉我们该终端在文件系统中的位置
Now the TDY command will actually tell us where this terminal is located where on the file system it
是。
is.
我们看到它与劈开开发人员劈开PTSA劈开一号一起回来了。
And we see it comes back with Slash dev slash PTSA slash one.
好的。
OK.
现在我要做的是重定向来自输入ATX磁带的内容。
Now what I'm going to do is I'm going to redirect the the the content from input ATX tape.
所以就像这样。
So just like this.
我不会将其写入文件，而是将其写入到此位置劈开定义劈开PTSA劈开
And instead of writing it to a file I'm going to write it to this location slash def slash PTSA slash
一个所以劈开定义劈开PTSA劈开一个。
one so slash def slash PTSA slash one.
好的。
OK.
当我按Enter键时，我的天哪，我们可以看到数据已经从一个终端传递到
And when I press Enter Oh my goodness we can see that the data has been passed from one terminal to
再来一杯。
another.
它现在有点像一个非常垃圾的即时消息系统，但这并不是特别有用
It's kind of like a really rubbish instant messaging system right now but this isn't particularly useful
就其本身而言。
in itself.
它显示了如何使用重定向在整个计算机甚至整个计算机上传递数据
It shows how redirection can be used to pass data around your entire computer and even over computer
我听说过的电视网。
networks I've heard.
所以这是相当令人惊讶的。
So that's pretty amazing.
真是太棒了。
So how awesome.
您知道，了解您需要了解的关于Linux中的重定向的一切，以及Linux系统的美妙之处
You know know everything you need to know about redirection in Linux and the beauty of the Linux system
应该开始变得清晰起来。
should begin to be making itself clear.
现在快速回顾一下，您了解到标准输入、标准输出和标准错误都是流
Now as a quick recap you learned that standard input standard output and standard error are streams
数据，就像普通的水流一样，从某个地方流到某个地方，然后重定向到某个地方
of data and like normal water streams that flow comes from somewhere and goes to somewhere redirection
就是控制我们使用重定向。
is all about controlling that we're using redirection.
您可以控制标准输出和标准错误流的位置，也可以控制标准输出和标准错误流的位置
You can control where standard output and standard error streams go and you can control where standard
输入来自。
input comes from.
您还了解到，这些数据流具有与其相关联的数字。
You also learned that these data streams have numbers associated with them.
标准输入为流编号0，标准输出流编号为1。
Standard Input is stream number 0 and standard output stream number one.
所以这个错误是第二号流。
And so that error is stream number two.
然后，您了解了可用于重定向的不同符号。
You then learned about the different symbols that can be used for redirection.
它们基本上是大于号和小于号。
They are basically the greater than and less than signs.
请记住，如果您要重定向输出，则灰色的无符号表示文件将被擦除
Just remember that if you're redirecting output one gray of unsigned means that the file will be erased
或者在你写之前被截断。
or truncated before you write to it.
因此，如果您不想丢失其中的数据。
So if you don't want to lose the data that's in there.
请确保使用大于号将数据追加到文件。
Make sure to use to greater than signs to append data to the file.
换句话说，将数据添加到已有的数据中。
In other words add data to what's already there.
现在，您可以使用重定向做一些更酷的事情，但它们不太常见
Now there are a few more cool things that you can do with redirection but they're less common than what
您已经在这最后几个视频中学到了。
you've learned in these last few videos.
如果你很好奇，我在课程资源里放了一个链接，你可以在那里了解更多关于重定向的知识。
So if you're curious I've put a link where you can learn more about redirection in the lecture resources.
但是有一个问题现在一定在您的脑海中挥之不去，那就是我如何才能将输出从一个
But one question that must be burning in your head right now is how can I redirect the output from one
命令传递给另一个人的输入。
command to the input of another.
肯定有办法的。
Surely there must be a way.
这个过程被称为管道，在我看来，这是Linux皇冠上的明珠
Well that process is known as piping and it is in my opinion that that's the crown jewel of the Linux
命令行管道可能是命令行允许您做的最重要的事情，因为它
command line piping is probably the most important thing that the command line lets you do because it
获取做一件事做得很好的所有命令，并允许您将它们绑定在一起
takes all of the commands that do one thing very very very well and allows you to tie them together
基本上可以无缝地做任何你想做的事。
seamlessly to do basically anything that you want.
掌握管道肯定会给你超能力，这样你才能掌握管道的力量，获得超能力。
Mastering piping would definitely give you superpowers so to master the power of piping and gain superpowers.
我将在下一个视频中见到你。
I'll see you in the next video.